Maximilian Allesch

Full Stack Web Developer Berlin, Germany

T: +49 151 61402059

E: max.allesch@gmx

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/max-allesch-2570649b/ Portfolio: https://mr-macko.github.io/portfolio-site/index.html

GitHub: https://github.com/Mr-Macko

SUMMARY

Junior Full-Stack Web Developer with a background in Performance Marketing and 6 years experience working together with different teams and stakeholders. Helped the student learning platform Studydrive to establish successfully in 5 Markets and supported several brands to grow their business. Able to quickly understand new circumstances and transform them into efficient and high performing web applications by using strong analytical and creative skills. Proficient at writing well-designed, testable and efficient code using current best practices in web development. Skilled in HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Angular and Node.js.

EDUCATION

Certification

Full-Stack Web Development

Sep 2021 - Apr 2022 CareerFoundry, Berlin

Bachelor of Arts
Media- & Eventmanagement

2012 - 2015

HMKW - Hochschule für Medien, Kommunikation & Wirtschaft, Berlin

SKILLS

Frontend Development

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript
- Libraries & Frameworks (React, Redux,Angular, Material, Bootstrap,SASS/SCSS, ¡Query)
- Responsive design, modals and touch interaction
- AJAX & JSON
- Version Control (Git)
- Test- & Behavior-Driven-Development (unit testing, integration testing, acceptance testing, and end-to-end testing)
- Continuous Integration / Delivery
- Functional & object oriented programming
- Mobile Apps (React Native, Expo)

Backend Development

- NodeJS & Express
- APIs (JSON, RESTful, Postman)
- Hosting & Web Services (AWS, Google, Firebase, Heroku, Netlify)
- Relational & non-relational databases (PostgreSQL, MongoDB)

Others

- Languages
 - German (native)
 - English (fluent)
 - o Italian (basic)
- Paid Social Marketing
- Search Engine Marketing
- Google Analytics
- Google Tag Manager
- Google Optimize
- Microsoft Excel
- Adobe Photoshop

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

MyFlix | CareerFoundry Project (Dec 2021 - Mar 2022)

- Created a non-relational database (MongoDB) to store user data and movie information.
- With Node.js and Express, I created a REST API that interacts with the database using Mongoose. I used Postman to test the API endpoints, generated clear and straightforward documentation, then used Heroku to deploy the API.
- Created two single-page, responsive front-end applications, one using React and the other Angular (both following the MVC design pattern) (with Angular Material). Users can register, browse the library, and bookmark their favorites.

React App Angular App API

Meet App | CareerFoundry Project (Feb 2022 - Apr 2022)

- Using React, I created a progressive web application (cross-platform, offline available) to display events (a list and charts) from a google calendar.
- User stories were translated into scenarios for unit and integration testing (Jest), acceptability testing (Cucumber), and end-to-end testing (Puppeteer).
- To authenticate and authorize users (OAuth) I implemented serverless functions with AWS lambda.

Meet App

WORK EXPERIENCE

AdStrive GmbH | Berlin (Sep 2021 - Present)

(Spin-off of the Claneo Performance Marketing team into its own agency.)

Claneo GmbH | Berlin (Apr 2021 - Aug 2021)

Performance Marketing Manager

 Supported a variety of clients strategically and operationally in their performance marketing activities (Paid Social, SEM, App Marketing, Tracking) to significantly increase their business and sales.

Studydrive GmbH | Berlin (Jan 2019 - Mar 2021)

Performance Marketing Manager

- Supervised all marketing activities (Paid Social, SEM, App Marketing) and helped the platform to grow successfully in 5 different markets.
- Implemented technical requirements for our marketing activities (conversion tracking, landing pages creation, conversion rate optimization) to increase the overall conversion rate and to improve the performance tracking.

mobileJobs GmbH | Berlin

Junior Online Marketing Manager (Sep 2016 - Dec 2018)

Internship Online Marketing (Apr 2016 - Aug 2016)

- Setup and optimization of ad campaigns (main focus on paid social)
- Increased the reach of our client's job ads by establishing collaborations with numerous job platforms and transmitting the job ads automatically via a XML-Interface.

